Toby Killen

24 Garnock Hill | Belfast | BT10 0AW | 07963459276 | Itoby24@gmail.com

Objective

Looking for a career change into a more opportunity filled job than my current employment.

Skills

Team work	Communication skills
Time management	Logical Thinking
Flexible and adaptive	Commercial awareness
Problem solving	 Leadership
Ability to work under pressure	Confidence
Retail experience (3.5 years)	IT skills
Resilience	Efficient and effective work flow
Dictated	Very Punctual

Experience

<u>Moor Park filling station, Blacks Road – Supervisor and Sales Assistant - September 2015 to Present (Current Employment)</u>

- Using POS systems for checkouts.
- Ensuring the customer is more than satisfied and providing an excellent service to the customers.
- Ensuring isles are faced off and fully stocked.
- Ensuring stock is date checked and removed if needed.
- Ensuring the floor clear and rubbish free and that it is of a standard of health and safety for customer, employee and colleague safety.
- Ensuring that all safety procedures are strictly following and adhered to.
- Working within a team, communicating with both customers and colleagues.
- Monitoring employee productivity.
- Tills Management.
- Key Holder Responsibilities.
- Organizing workflow and ensuring that employees understand their tasks.

Kainos - Work Experience -1 Week - 19th October 2015 to 22nd October 2015

- Developing simple scripts on scratch.
- Developing and learning Python Language and writing basic scripts within python.
- Working within a team, communicating and sharing ideas.
- Learning and understanding Linux based system directories.

Montupet - 1 Day work experience

- Learning and understanding problem solving methods e.g. 5 Whys?
- Learning the importance of following instructions strictly.
- Working within a team, allocating tasks to each other to get the job done.

Lloyds Banking Group - 1-week work experience

- Understanding the importance of customer service and how it may affect the company.
- Shadowing staff on calls, understanding why customer satisfaction is important to the company.
- Talking to Team Leaders, understanding the importance of happy staff making happy customers

Education & Qualifications

University of Ulster (2018-2022)

Qualification	<u>Grade</u>
Software Engineering - BEng	Pending
	· -

Malone Integrated College (2011-2018)

Qualification	<u>Grade</u>
<u>A-Levels</u>	
A-Level Sport and exercise sciences	Grade A*
A-Level Engineering	Grade A*
A-Level Applied ICT	Grade B
GCES	
GCSE English	Grade B
GCSE Maths	Grade B
GCSE Further Maths	Grade C
GCSE Business	Grade B
GCSE Moving Images	Grade B
GCSE ICT	Grade C
GCSE Religion	Grade B
GCSE Princes Trust Personal Development	Grade C

PERSONAL STATEMENT

My name is Toby, I'm 19 years old with currently employed as a General Sales assistant providing an excellent customer service and working effectively within a team. Currently been working with for 3 years of retail experience and would like to change my career into a more opportunity filled job than my current employment, so I can work with career progression and university studies. I am currently at university of Ulster, studying software engineering. I am a hardworking, logical thinker within the work place and I can apply myself as much as I can within the work place. I can provide team working skills and low-level management to other members of staff. I am currently still in school studying ICT, Engineering and Sports. I wish to go onto ulster university in September 2018 to study Software engineering. Being currently employed, I wish to move on and develop my current skills and learn new ones. I pay close attention to standard of work required within the work place and I thrive to exceed the expectations that people expect of me. I think in a logical way and I place myself into a position where everyone works well in a team environment which I think is appropriate to ensure that we reach the same goal. Whilst I was in school, I played in a table tennis team, and Being part of a successful table tennis team, I work well in a team, communicating and fast pace thinking. Throughout the last 3 years of education, I have been employed and studying as well showing I can manage both school and work now and later in the foreseeable future. I wish to have a change in my career and take on any opportunity I see that will allow more doors to be open for me and if I want to progress through them, improving my career.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Within my spare time, I like to go to the gym, cycle and play table tennis. I have participated within several table tennis events both in and outside of school and have successfully place top three in two of them. 1st place in the Ulster U16s School Team event and 3rd in the All Ireland finals school team event. I also enjoy going out with my friends, socialising and meeting new people.

I like to follow the latest technology releases and mobile app development. When I'm doing school work I like to listen to music and sometimes I would give my hands a break and solve puzzles. I tend to pick up a Rubik's cube and solve them. I think these are the funniest as they are logical puzzles and they get more difficult the bigger you go ranging from the 2x2 up to the 5x5. I also like to learn new programming like java and C#, I don't know much of it as I don't have time to learn it all with school and work but slowly but surely overtime it will come to me. I also like writing HTML and CSS and I think these languages make the most sense and are the most logical. Using HTML and CSS I made a website for my ICT project which I completed quite quickly.

Also, I like to learn about software, programming, apps, websites and computers. I built my 1st custom PC about 2 years ago and I've been a custom PC enthusiast ever since. Over time, I've just been upgrading it swapping out parts every so often making it a beast that it is today.

I've took an interest in apps and their business success e.g. Snapchat, Facebook etc and how they became from a start-up to a world class success. I've always been motivated and inspired by start-up app that are so simple but so effective that they changed the world turning their simplicity into millions.

References

Mr Talbot Year Head Malone College 45 Finaghy Road North BT10 0JB 028 90 38 1988

Mr English Careers Teacher Malone College 45 Finaghy Road North BT10 0JB 028 90 38 1988